Volume-based factors usually include price information,
基于交易量的因子通常包含价格信息
to categorize the volume in a given time period as a net buy or net sell.
将给定时段的交易量分类为净买入或净卖出
At first glance, the idea of net buying or net selling,
咋一看 净买入或净卖出
may appear counterintuitive when you recall,
可能违反直觉
that every transaction involves a buyer and a seller.
因为每个交易都涉及买家和卖家
Some examples will help to clarify what we mean by this.
为了帮助你理解含义 下面举几个例子
A volume factor may track whether
交易量因子会跟踪
the total trading volume of a stock is higher than normal,
股票的总交易量是否高于正常量
and use that to determine whether recent price movements are significant or not.
并判断最近的价格变动是否显著
For example, sometimes stock exchanges are open on or around a major holiday,
例如 有时候证交所在大型节假日当天或前后开盘
and since fewer investors are participating in trading,
因为参与交易的投资者更少
volume may be lower on these days.
所以交易量可能会更低
So investors will take the low volume into consideration,
投资者在考虑价格变化是否显著时
when deciding whether price movements are significant or not.
就会考虑到交易量较低
Volume can help add more context to a price-based factor,
交易量可以为基于价格的因子提供更多背景信息
such as a moment factor.
例如动量因子
For instance, unusually high volumes that accompanies a major price movement,
例如 伴随重大价格变化的异常高交易量
may be a sign that the momentum signal is more significant than usual.
可能表示动量信号比平时更显著
One could say that the price-based momentum factor,
基于价格的动量因子
is conditioned on the volume information.
以交易量信息为基础
One piece of volume data that is independent of price is called short interest.
与价格无关的一种交易量数据是做空比例
Short interest tracks the quantity of a stock shares,
做空比例会跟踪
which are held short.
做空的股数
When a trader shorts a stock,
当交易者做空股票时
they borrow the stock from its owner and sell it,
他们会向股票所有者借股票并卖出
with a hope of buying the stock back at a later date when it's cheaper.
希望在未来股票便宜时买入
If instead, the stock price increases,
如果股价上涨
the short seller will realize mark to market losses.
做空卖方就会出现按市价计价损失
Mark to market is an accounting concept,
按市价计价是一个会计概念
that assess the value of a health asset at its market price.
即以市价对持有的资产进行计价
So mark to market losses,
所以按市价计价损失
are unrealized losses that are tracked in accounting,
是在会计中跟踪的未实现损失
even if the asset isn't sold to realize those losses.
即使资产尚未出售并实现这些损失
This can become expensive if the stock price keeps rising,
如果股价继续上涨 损失可能会变高
so short-sellers may decide to cut their losses,
所以做空卖家可能会决定
by buying the stock at the market price,
以市价买入股票并平仓
and closing out their position.
达到止损目的
This is called a short squeeze.
这称为轧空
If this sounds a bit complicated,
如果听起来有点复杂的话
consider the mirror image of a short squeeze,
轧空的对立面
which is a long squeeze.
就是轧多
If you bought stock in a retail company,
如果你买入零售股
and watch the stock price decline day after day,
并且眼看着股价一天天的下跌
you might have decided at some point to cut your losses and sell the stock.
你可能在某一天决定止损并卖出股票
This long squeeze is the mirror image of a short squeeze.
这种轧多就是轧空的对立面
When a short squeeze occurs due to an upward price movement,
股价上涨导致轧空后
the additional stock buying that it triggers,
触发的额外买入行为
tends to add more upward momentum to the stock price.
往往使股价出现更多的上涨动量
So if recent short interests is higher than usual,
如果最近的做空比例比平时高
this might be considered a buy signal.
那么可以视作买入信号
Since an increase in price,
因为股价上涨
may trigger a domino effect of additional increases.
可能会触发进一步上涨的多米勒效应
This could motivate a nice Alpha factor.
这可能会形成不错的 Alpha 因子
Find stocks that have high price momentum,
寻找股价动量很高
and are highly shorted.
并且高度做空的股票
In this case, short interest data could act as a conditioning information,
在这种情况下 做空比例可以作为条件信息
to make a momentum signal stronger.
使动量信号更强